Guide to the Clifton R. Merritt Papers 1935-2008
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- The American Wilderness Alliance / American Wildlands, 1957-2007; Series IV; 29.5 linear feet
  - Subject Files, 1957-2007; Subseries 2; 20.5 linear feet
    - Scapegoat-Miscellaneous, 1968-2002 (Box-folder 96/15)
    - Brian Schweitzer, Correspondence, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 96/16)
    - Scotchman Peak Wilderness Study Area, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 96/17-19)
    - Selway-Bitterroot National Forest-Grizzly Bear Reintroduction, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 97/1)
    - Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness-Bitterroot and Lolo National Forests, 1969-1998 (Box-folder 97/2)
    - Seniors for Wilderness, 1988 (Box-folder 97/3)
    - September Addendum to Deerlodge Forest Area, 1998 (Box-folder 97/4)
    - Sheep Mountain Logging, 1987 (Box-folder 97/5)
    - Shoshone District Wilderness Study Area, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 97/6)
    - Sierra Borealis, 1987 (Box-folder 97/7)
    - Sierra Club Suit-Water, 1985 (Box-folder 97/8)
    - Ski Yellowstone, 1983 (Box-folder 97/9)
    - Sleeping Child Wilderness, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 97/10)
    - Smith River, 1986 (Box-folder 97/11)
    - Snowmobiling on Public Lands, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 97/12)
    - South San Juan Wilderness Expansion, 1981 (Box-folder 97/13)
    - South San Juans-Draft Report, 1982 (Box-folder 97/14)
    - South San Juans-Grizzly Incident, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 97/15)
    - South San Juans-Rio Grande National Forest, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 97/16)
    - Southeast Alaska Conservation Council, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 97/17)
    - Southeast Alaska-Tongass Timber Reform, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 97/18)
    - Special Appeals, 1986-1993 (Box-folder 97/19)
    - Special Pieces on Wildlands and Wildlife, Clifton Merritt, 1970-1998 (Box-folder 97/20)
    - Speeches and Statements, Clifton Merritt, 1978-1999 (Box-folder 97/21)
    - Speeches on Wilderness, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 97/22)
    - Stateline Snowmobile Analysis-Idaho and Montana, 1997 (Box-folder 98/1)
    - Stony Mountain, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 98/2)
    - Sunday Session Summaries, Annual Western Wilderness and Rivers Conference, 1980 (Box-folder 98/3)
    - Tatshenshini-Alsek Rivers, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 98/4)
    - Taylor-Hilgard, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 98/5)
    - Taylor-Hilgard Wilderness Study Area, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 98/6)
    - Ten Lakes Wilderness Study Area, 1991 (Box-folder 98/7)
    - Ten Lakes Wilderness Study Area, 1998 (Box-folder 98/8)
    - Ten Lakes, Montana, 1980 (Box-folder 98/9)
    - Tenderfoot Deep Creek, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 98/10)
    - The Economic Effects of Timber Harvesting on Recreational and Commercial Fisheries and Municipal Watersheds," by John B. Loomis, 1987 (Box-folder 98/11-12)
    - Theodore Roosevelt Conservation Alliance, undated (Box-folder 98/13)
    - Timber Articles and Clippings, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 98/14)
    - Timber Trends, 1992 (Box-folder 98/15)
    - Tin Cup Dam-Selway-Bitterroot Wilderness, 1997 (Box-folder 98/16)
    - Tishomingo National Wildlife Refuge, 1995 (Box-folder 98/17)
    - Tobacco Road Roadless Area-Deerlodge National Forest, 1981 (Box-folder 98/18)
    - Tongue River Breaks-Custer National Forest, 1979 (Box-folder 98/19)
    - Trail Creek Lawsuit, 1995 (Box-folder 98/20)
    - Trail Creek Lawsuit-Beaverhead National Forest, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 98/21)
    - Travel Brochures, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 98/22)
    - Trip Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 99/1)
    - Trout Unlimited Newsletter-Flaming Gorge/Lower Green River Chapter, 1997 (Box-folder 99/2)
    - Tsongas-Roth Alaska Lands Bill, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 99/3)
    - Tuchuck Wilderness Study Area-Flathead and Kootenai National Forests, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 99/4)
    - Two Forks Dam, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 99/5)
    - Two Forks Dam, 1987-2006 (Box-folder 99/6)
    - United Sportsman's Foundation-Articles of Incorporation), undated (Box-folder 99/7)
    - United Sportsman's Foundation-Tax-Deductible Internal Revenue Service), 1979 (Box-folder 99/8)
    - United States Forest Service, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 99/9)
    - United States Forest Service-Shared Views Newsletter, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 99/10)
    - Upper Missouri Breaks National Monument, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 99/11)
    - Upper Missouri River Breaks National Monument-Bureau of Land Management, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 99/12)
    - Utah, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 99/13)
    - Utah Bureau of Land Management: Conservationists Wilderness Proposal, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 99/14)
    - Utah Wilderness Association, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 99/15)
    - Utah Wilderness Association, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 99/16-17)
    - Utah Wilderness Association, 1991 (Box-folder 100/1)
    - Utah Wilderness Coalition, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 100/2-3)
    - Utah Wilderness, Bureau of Land Management, 1972-1990 (Box-folder 100/4-6)
    - Wall Canyon Wilderness Study Area, 1987 (Box-folder 100/7)
    - Washington Wilderness Coalition, Washington Wildfire, 1987 (Box-folder 100/8)
    - Wasting Disease Clippings, 1999 (Box-folder 100/9)
    - Water Pollution, 1996 (Box-folder 100/10)
    - Water Rights for Wilderness Areas, 1987 (Box-folder 100/11)
    - Watershed Economics Grant Proposal-Dr. John B. Loomis, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 100/12-14)
    - Weminuche Wilderness-Colorado. San Juan National Forest, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 101/1)
    - West Big Hole, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 101/2)
    - West Big Hole Wilderness Proposal, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 101/3)
    - West Pioneer, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 101/4)
    - West Pioneers Wilderness Study Area, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 101/5)
    - Western States General, 1987 (Box-folder 101/6)
    - Western Wilderness and Rivers Conference, 1980 (Box-folder 101/7)
    - Western Wilderness Calendar, 1983 (Box-folder 101/8)
    - Westlope Cutthroat Trout Campaign, 1997 (Box-folder 101/9)
    - Westslope Cutthroat Trout Clippings, 1992-2005 (Box-folder 101/10)
    - Westslope Cutthroat Trout Symposium, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 101/11)
    - Whitetail-Haystack-O'Neil (WHO) Roadless Area-Deerlodge National Forest-Paul Richards' Correspondence, 1997 (Box-folder 101/12)
    - Wild Idaho Conference, 1990 (Box-folder 101/13)
    - Wild Missouri Wilderness Proposal Correspondence-Bureau of Land Management, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 101/14)
    - Wild Rockies Wilderness, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 101/15)
    - Wilderness Article Drafts, 1991 (Box-folder 101/16)
    - Wilderness Article Drafts and Editing, 1982-1998 (Box-folder 101/17)
    - Wilderness Article Drafts and Notes, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 101/18)
    - Wilderness Articles, 1967-2001 (Box-folder 101/19)
    - Wilderness Associated Wildlife-Montana, 1978 (Box-folder 101/20)
    - Wilderness Clippings, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 102/1)
    - Wilderness Economics, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 102/2)
    - Wilderness Economics, 1987 (Box-folder 102/3)
    - Wilderness Education, 1988 (Box-folder 102/4)
    - Wilderness Highlights, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 102/5)
    - Wilderness Institute, undated (Box-folder 102/6)
    - Wilderness Leaders Conference, 1987 (Box-folder 102/7)
    - Wilderness Management, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 102/8)
    - Wilderness Management Dilemma-David N. Cole and Draft of Bill Worf Response, 1996 (Box-folder 102/9)
    - Wilderness Management-Bill Worf, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 102/10)
    - Wilderness Movement and National Forests: 1964-1980-Dennis Roth's Draft, 1983 (Box-folder 102/11)
    - Wilderness Society-American Wildlands Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 102/12)
    - Wilderness Society-Wilderness Proposals, 1983-2002 (Box-folder 102/13-14)
    - Wilderness Watch, 1997-2004 (Box-folder 102/15)
    - Wilderness Watch Board, Notes, Minutes, Correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 103/1)
    - Wilderness Watch-Bill Worf, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 103/2-3)
    - Wilderness Watcher, 1998-2003 (Box-folder 103/4)
    - Wildland Economic Studies, 1980-1995 (Box-folder 103/5-6)
    - Wildlife Distribution and Proposed Montana Wilderness Maps, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 123/)
    - Wildlife Economics, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 103/7)
    - Wildlife-Hunting-Colorado Wilderness Bill, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 103/8)
    - Tim Wirth-Senate Campaign and Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 103/9)
    - Hazel Wolf, Speeches, 1997 (Box-folder 103/10)
    - Words on Wilderness-The Wildlands Studies and Information Center, 1996 (Box-folder 103/11)
    - Worf Family Memorial Wilderness Scholarship, 1997 (Box-folder 103/12)
    - Written Statements and Remarks, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 103/13)
    - Wyoming Chapter of the Sierra Club, 2002 (Box-folder 103/14)
    - Wyoming Outdoor Council Annual Meeting, 1988 (Box-folder 103/15)
    - Wyoming Wildlife Federation, Response to Governor Geringer's "Gag Order" on State Agencies, 1995 (Box-folder 103/16)
    - Wyoming Wildlife Summit, 1994 (Box-folder 103/17)
    - Yellowstone National Park-Snowmobile Issue, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 103/18)
    - Yellowstone to Yukon, 1993 and undated (Box-folder 103/19)
    - Yellowstone to Yukon Biodiversity Strategy, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 103/20)
    - Yellowstone to Yukon Conservation Initiative, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 103/21)
    - Yellowstone to Yukon Conservation Initiative, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 103/22)
    - Yellowstone to Yukon Project, Memos and Correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 104/1)
    - Yellowstone to Yukon Strategy, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 104/2)
    - Dennis Zadra, Resource Specialist, Correspondence and Reports, 1994 (Box-folder 104/3)
  - Corridors of Life Program, 1985-2006; Subseries 3; 1.5 linear feet
    - Corridor Mapping, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 104/4)
    - Corridors of Life, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 104/5-6)
    - Corridors of Life, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 104/7-8)
    - Corridors of Life, 1994-2003 (Box-folder 104/9)
    - Corridors of Life, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 104/10)
    - Corridors of Life, 1997 (Box-folder 104/11)
    - Corridors of Life, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 104/12)
    - Corridors of Life-Board Meeting, 1993 (Box-folder 104/13)
    - Corridors of Life-Feasibility Study, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 104/14)
    - Corridors of Life-Feasibility Study, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 105/1)
    - Corridors of life-Funding and Grants, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 105/2)
    - Corridors of Life-Model Building Phase, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 105/3)
    - Corridors of Life-Outreach Mailers, undated (Box-folder 105/4)
    - Corridors of Life-Outreach Proposals, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 105/5)
    - Corridors of Life-Strategy, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 105/6-7)
    - Corridors of Life-Wildlife Corridors Grant Proposals, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 105/8-11)
    - Corridors Research-Bighorn Sheep, 1994 (Box-folder 105/12)
    - Corridors Research-Bison, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 105/13)
    - Corridors Research-Buffalo, 1998 (Box-folder 105/14)
    - Corridors Research-Bull Trout, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 105/15)
    - Corridors Research-Bull trout, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 105/16)
    - Corridors Research-Cutthroat Trout, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 106/1)
    - Corridors Research-Eagle, 1992 (Box-folder 106/2)
    - Corridors Research-Elk, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 106/3)
    - Corridors Research-Geese, 1996 (Box-folder 106/4)
    - Corridors Research-Grayling, 1994 (Box-folder 106/5)
    - Corridors Research-Grizzly Bear, 1986-2000 (Box-folder 106/6-7)
    - Corridors Research-Grizzly Bear Recovery, 1988-2000 (Box-folder 106/8)
    - Corridors Research-Lynx, 1990 (Box-folder 106/9)
    - Corridors Research-Mule Deer, 1996 (Box-folder 106/10)
    - Corridors Research-Owl, 1990 (Box-folder 106/11)
    - Corridors Research-Rainbow Trout, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 106/12)
    - Corridors Research-Wolf, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 106/13)
    - Corridors Research-Wolverine, Lynx, Fisher, 1995 (Box-folder 106/14)
    - Corridors Research-Woodland Caribou, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 106/15)
    - Forest Environments, Montana Biological Survey: Corridors of Life-Student Letters, 1998 (Box-folder 106/16)
    - Program Director, Corridors of Life, 1994 (Box-folder 106/17)
    - Wildlife Corridors, 1991-2006 (Box-folder 107/1-3)
    - Wildlife Corridors in the Northern Rockies, 1993 (Box-folder 107/4)
  - Organizational Publications and Newsletters, 1979-2007; Subseries 4; 2.5 linear feet
    - Annual Review and Report Mailers, 1993-2004 (Box-folder 107/5)
    - It's Time To Go Wild Newsletter, Drafts and Correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 107/6)
    - It's Time To Go Wild Newsletter, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 107/7)
    - Material Used for Summer/Fall Issue, On the Wild Side, 1995 (Box-folder 107/8)
    - Miscellaneous Member Mailers, undated (Box-folder 107/9)
    - Miscellaneous Organizational Publications and Mailers, undated (Box-folder 107/10)
    - Newsletter Drafts and Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 107/11)
    - On the Wild Side, Article Drafts, 1992 (Box-folder 107/12)
    - On the Wild Side, Article Drafts, 1994 (Box-folder 107/13)
    - On the Wild Side, Articles and Correspondence, 1994 (Box-folder 107/14)
    - On the Wild Side, Articles Drafts and Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 107/15)
    - On the Wild Side, Article Drafts and Correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 107/16)
    - On the Wild Side, Cartoons for issue, 1994 and undated (Box-folder 108/1)
    - On the Wild Side, Copy for the Next Journal, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 108/2)
    - On the Wild Side, Correspondence, 1994 (Box-folder 108/3)
    - On the Wild Side, Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 108/4)
    - On the Wild Side, Correspondence and Articles, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 108/5)
    - On the Wild Side, Correspondence with Ecos, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 108/6)
    - On the Wild Side, Correspondence, 1994 (Box-folder 108/7)
    - On the Wild Side, Draft and Copies, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 108/8)
    - On the Wild Side, Draft and Copies, 1987 (Box-folder 108/9)
    - On the Wild Side, Edited Draft, 1997 (Box-folder 108/10)
    - On the Wild Side, Clifton R. Merritt Articles, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 108/11)
    - On the Wild Side, Special Issue Correspondence and Article Drafts, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 108/12)
    - On the Wild Side, Unedited Copy, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 108/13)
    - On the Wild Side, Used Drafts, 1994 (Box-folder 108/14)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 109/1)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 109/2)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 109/3)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 109/4)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 109/5)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 109/6)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 109/7)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 109/8)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 109/9)
    - On the Wild Side, Newsletters, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 110/1)
    - Wild America Publications, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 110/2)
    - Wild America Publications, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 110/3)
    - Wild America Publications, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 110/4)
- Friends of the Bitterroot, 1991-2006; Series V; 0.5 linear feet
  Friends of the Bitterroot is a forest-watch organization based in Hamilton, Montana. This series contains meeting memos, notes, correspondence, and newsletters.
  - Meeting Agendas, Memos, and Internal Correspondence, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 110/5)
  - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1992 (Box-folder 110/6)
  - Meeting Notes and Memos, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 110/7)
  - Memos, and Internal Correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 110/8)
  - Friends of the Bitterroot News, 1998-2006 (Box-folder 110/9)
- Personal Materials, 1935-2007; Series VI; 5.5 linear feet
  This series is arranged into two subseries. Subseries 1, Writings and Files, contains drafts, correspondence, articles, and publications. Subseries 2, Miscellaneous Materials, consists of a scrapbook, a yearbook, and rolodexes.
  - Writings and Files, 1935-2007; Subseries 1; 2.5 linear feet
    - Beyond the Roads, 1985-2003 (Box-folder 110/10)
    - Beyond the Roads, undated (Box-folder 110/11)
    - Beyond the Roads, Book Chapter Drafts and Notes, 1992-2006 and undated (Box-folder 110/12)
    - Beyond the Roads, Book Chapters, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 110/13)
    - Beyond the Roads, Book Chapters and Writing Submissions-Wilderness and Wilderness Policy, 1990 (Box-folder 110/14)
    - Beyond the Roads, Chapters, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 110/15)
    - Beyond the Roads, Chapters, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 111/1)
    - Beyond the Roads, Chapters for the book, 2005 and undated (Box-folder 111/2)
    - Beyond the Roads, Older Drafts, 1975-2005 (Box-folder 111/3)
    - Conquest of the Land through 7,000 Years, 1953-1983 (Box-folder 111/4)
    - Employment Applications and Correspondence, 1946 (Box-folder 111/5)
    - Grandfather, 2005 (Box-folder 111/6)
    - Grandfather Copy, undated (Box-folder 111/7)
    - Grandfather Merritt, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 111/8)
    - Grandfather Merritt, Finished Chapters, 2005-2007 (Box-folder 111/9)
    - High School Writings and Report Cards, undated (Box-folder 111/10)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, 2001 (Box-folder 111/11)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, undated (Box-folder 112/1)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, Draft, 2003 (Box-folder 112/2)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, Draft, 2003 (Box-folder 112/3)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, Draft, 2005 (Box-folder 112/4)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, Draft, undated (Box-folder 112/5)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, Draft-includes Brother Don, but not Sister Bernice, undated (Box-folder 112/6)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, Drafts, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 112/7)
    - I Remember my Grandfather, Drafts, Notes, Research, 1991-2006 (Box-folder 113/1-4)
    - Information Requests and Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 113/5)
    - Memoirs, Copies of Photos for, undated (Box-folder 113/6)
    - Memoirs, Correspondence Regarding, 1997-2006 (Box-folder 113/7)
    - Memoirs of Grandfather Merritt, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 113/8)
    - Clifton Merritt, Older Articles, 1965 and undated (Box-folder 113/9)
    - Clifton Merritt, Oral History Interview Transcripts, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 113/10)
    - Miscellaneous Book Chapter Drafts, 2006 and undated (Box-folder 113/11)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1971-2005 (Box-folder 113/12)
    - Poems and Songs, Drafts, 1937-1941 and undated (Box-folder 113/13)
    - Poems and Songs, Drafts, undated (Box-folder 114/1)
    - Poetry and Song Notebooks, 1935-1939 and undated (Box-folder 114/2-3)
    - Poetry and Song Notebooks, undated (Box-folder 114/4-5)
    - Poetry and Song Notes and Drafts, 1935 and undated (Box-folder 114/6-8)
    - Publications, 1946-1986 (Box-folder 115/1-2)
    - Poem Clipping-Published Copy, undated (Box-folder 115/3)
    - Recollections in the Conservation Movement, 1985 (Box-folder 115/4)
    - Jeanine Ricketts, 1972-2005 (Box-folder 115/5)
    - Scapegoat Book Chapter Copies, undated (Box-folder 115/6)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1940-1998 and undated; Subseries 2; 3.0 linear feet
    - Helena High School Yearbook, "The Vigilante", 1940 (Box-folder 115/7)
    - Rolodex, undated (Box 117)
    - 4 rolodexes, undated (Box 118)
    - Scrapbook, 1998 (Box 119)
- Awards, 1972-2007; Series VII; 5.75 linear feet
  This series is arranged into two subseries. Subseries 1, Subject Files and Correspondence, and Subseries 2, Certificates, Statuettes, and Plaques.
  - Subject Files and Correspondence, 1972-2007; Subseries 1; 0.5 linear feet
    - American Motors Award, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 116/1)
    - American Motors Conservation Award, 1973-1996 (Box-folder 116/2)
    - Conservation Award Correspondence and Clippings, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 116/3)
    - Gift Sketch from Montana Wilderness Association, 1984 (Box-folder 116/4)
    - Montana Wilderness Association Award, 1990 (Box-folder 116/5)
    - University of Montana Commencement Program and Manual, 2007 (Box-folder 116/6)
    - Proposal for Honorary Degree, Suppoting Documents, circa 1970-2005; Photocopies of documents gathered to support honorary degree proposal. The original documents likely exist elsewhere in the collection. (Box-folder 116/7)
    - 'Photocopies from Blue Binder', circa 1970-2005; Photocopies of documents likely gathered to support honorary award proposals. The original documents likely exist elsewhere in the collection. (Box-folder 116/8)
  - Certificates, Statuettes, and Plaques, 1976-2007; Subseries 2; 5.25 linear feet
    - University of Montana Honorary Doctoral Degree Certificate, 2007 (Box 120)
    - American Motors Award Plaque, 1976 (Box 120)
    - American Motors Award Framed Certificate, 1976 (Box 120)
    - Frank Church Award Certificate and Award Correspondence-Unframed, 1981 (Box 121)
    - Friends of the Bitterroot Lifetime Achievement Award Framed Certificate, 2003 (Box 121)
    - Nick Kramis Award Framed Certificate, 2005 (Box 121)
    - Award Plaque, undated (Box 122)
    - Nick Kramis Award Statuette, 2005 (Box 123)
    - University of Montana Graduation Cap and Tassel, 2007 (Box 123)
- Photographs, Series VIII; 5.2 linear feet
  This series primarily contains images of back country and wilderness areas. There are some photographs of Clif Merritt, his family, and individuals who were associated with The Wilderness Society. This series is currently unprocessed.
  - Slides, ca. 1950s-1970s (Box 125-127)
  - Prints, ca. 1950s-1970s (Box 128-129)
- Motion Picture Films, Series IX; 14 16mm films
  This series contains fourteen 16mm home movies primarily featuring outdoor recreation, family, and the Glacier National Park fish hatchery.
  - Untitled, ca. 1950s; Shots of body of water - possibly Flathead Lake; 16 mm; Color, 2 ft, No Sound (Reel 1)
  - Untitled, ca. 1950s; Glacier National Park Fish Hatchery - shots of hatchery and workers, shots of workers loading fish into truck then releasing into pond or lake (unknown location); 16 mm; Color, 50 ft, No Sound (Reel 2)
  - Untitled, ca. 1955; Shots of passenger train; 16 mm; Color, 5 ft, No Sound (Reel 3)
  - Untitled, ca. 1974; Shots of family decorating Christmas tree with tinsel and wrapping presents and placing them under the tree. Includes shots of baby.; 16 mm; Color, 50 ft, No Sound (Reel 4)
  - Untitled, ca. 1977; Shots of two men fishing on river (unknown loactaion), one man may have been Clifton Merritt; 16 mm; Color, 50 ft, No Sound (Reel 5)
  - Untitled, ca. 1976; Shots of two men fishing on river (unknown location), Two children sledding - dog in one shot; 16 mm; Color, 50 ft, No Sound (Reel 6)
  - Untitled, ca. 1974; Shots of baby shoes in crib; 16 mm; Color, 2 ft, No Sound (Reel 7)
  - Untitled, ca. 1976; Shots of forest and mountain, shots of men fishing; 16 mm; Color, 50 ft, No Sound (Reel 8)
  - Elk Hunting on Quintonknon Creek, ca. 1952; Elk Hunting on Quintonknon Creek - Shots of hunting camp and hunters packing out elk; 16 mm; Color, 50 ft, No Sound (Reel 9)
  - Untitled, ca. 1974; Shots of child sitting in high-chair eating meal and drinking milk. Shots of child eating lollipop; 16 mm; Color, 50 ft, No Sound (Reel 10)
  - Untitled, March 14, 1955; Shots of car entering West Glacier. Shots of child fishing. Shots of Lake McDonald; 16 mm; Color, 30 ft, No Sound (Reel 11)
  - Untitled, ca. 1974; Shots of family walking out of house and getting into car with baby and child. Shots of child and baby playing near river with mother. Shots of child and baby playing in car. Shots of baby in high-chair. Shots of baby in crib. Shots of beby crawling and walking. Shots of baby's first birthday.; 16 mm; Color, 200 ft, No Sound (Reel 12)
  - Glacier National Park Fish Hatchery, ca. 1976; Shots of Glacier National Park fish hatchery. Shots of catching fish in hatchery and loading them on truck. Shots of Tally Lake Ranger Station. Shots of releasing fish into Tally Lake. Shots of Trail Creek. Shots of men netting fish and dog splashing in water. Shots of collecting fish eggs.; 16 mm; Color, 200 ft, No Sound (Reel 13)